<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>climate mitigation | Eviota</title>
    <link>https://eviota.eu/tag/climate-mitigation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://eviota.eu/tag/climate-mitigation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>climate mitigation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://eviota.eu/media/icon_hucb5b60c3ce6d78a39dc1b8454aefe125_21353_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>climate mitigation</title>
      <link>https://eviota.eu/tag/climate-mitigation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Drought Risk Uninsurable?</title>
      <link>https://eviota.eu/post/2021-04-23-belgium-flood-insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eviota.eu/post/2021-04-23-belgium-flood-insurance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climate change is real and it is everywhere. Whereas island nations in
the Pacific are threatened with rising sea levels, Europe suffers from
ever more frequent scorching summers and resulting drought. Take the
case of Belgium, where heat waves in 2018 or 2020 have exacerbated an
already fragile drought risk profile. An all too tangible effect is that
houses built in areas where groundwater reservoirs are dwindling start
to rupture. What adds insult to injury is that insurers appear unwilling
to pay for damages: these climate-related risks simply did not feature
in insurance policies made up decades ago. The public and the media have
called upon the secretary of state responsible for consumer protection
to come up with a solution. (Download this
document in &lt;a href=&#34;https://eviota.eu/documents/Belgium-flood-risk-open-data.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Belgian insurance sector and government are currently investigating
how to address the ecological and financial issue. Should the risk
premium be raised on all insurance policies in an effort to spread risk,
or should only policy holders in designated risk areas be subject to a
raise in premia? Should urban planning initiatives and real estate
projects be required to assess these new types of risk beforehand?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driven by the Open Data Directive, we went in search for data at
government websites such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://waterinfo.be/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;waterinfo.be&lt;/a&gt;. That
proved harder than you would want, with quite a number of technological
barriers to cross. We independently explored the matter ourselves and
came up with this: a dynamic map that pictures the spatial distribution
of drought risk - as measured by a climate indicator known as the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://sac.csic.es/spei/map/maps.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;standardised recipitation-evapotranspiration
index&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-actual-drying-soil&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Actual drying soil.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/belgium_spei_2018_hu053711948486f3d03232ef0d63e51704_295716_85cb3a3e9d67ae93c4b48d13c76f103f.webp 400w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/belgium_spei_2018_hu053711948486f3d03232ef0d63e51704_295716_732c5a4fed2e5086cd4649603e01bc64.webp 760w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/belgium_spei_2018_hu053711948486f3d03232ef0d63e51704_295716_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://eviota.eu/media/img/blogposts_2021/belgium_spei_2018_hu053711948486f3d03232ef0d63e51704_295716_85cb3a3e9d67ae93c4b48d13c76f103f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Actual drying soil.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This SPEI index, measured as a standardized variate, shows the
deviations of the current climatic balance (precipitation minus
evapotranspiration potential) in the long run and is presented on a
monthly basis. As the SPEI in this form is more predictive for flood
risk, we simply inverted the index to suggest a measure of drought
risk&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Readers familiar with the “Kingdom by the sea” will remark that Belgium
cannot possibly have a lack of precipitation. It rains more than the
average Belgian cares for in the country. As a result, the water
management system has historically been based on getting the water out
as quickly as possible to the sea, in particular through the Ijzer,
Schelde and Maas rivers. Add the abundance of concrete in the densely
populated country - and its grossly mismanaged urban planning - and the
capacity to hold water in surface and ground reservoirs is severely
impaired. With climate change in full swing, these historical practices
come back to haunt Belgium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-belgians-aware-of-climate-risk&#34;&gt;Are Belgians aware of climate risk?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We projected the public opinion data from Eurobarometer 90.2 (fieldwork:
October-November 2018.) on the municipal map of Belgium. We used the
answers to the multiple choice question
&lt;code&gt;QB1 Do you think that the following extreme weather events are due to climate change?&lt;/code&gt;
We highlighted areas where people find it more likely to be exposed to
&lt;code&gt;Droughts and wildfires.&lt;/code&gt; We used the GESIS datafile (European
Commission 2019) and used the (Antal 2021b, 2021a) packages to project
the values to municipalities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see a weak spatial correlation between awareness of drought risk and
actual draught risk. The least affected parts of Belgium appear least
concerned. Despite its weakness, authorities and insurers can at least
build their mitigation policies on a hypothesis of positive correlation.
Of note is that concern for climate change effects follows regional,
linguistic and other patterns. The map in particular suggests the
Belgian provinces as markers for awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-perception-of-likely-drought&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Perception of likely drought.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/belgium_response_2018_hu47aa5cc947047eed9c66d363c68d4890_303964_e9673e15410217a2a4c7bb862bf2154f.webp 400w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/belgium_response_2018_hu47aa5cc947047eed9c66d363c68d4890_303964_d056770abb0309766c1c85bcf1ece158.webp 760w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/belgium_response_2018_hu47aa5cc947047eed9c66d363c68d4890_303964_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://eviota.eu/media/img/blogposts_2021/belgium_response_2018_hu47aa5cc947047eed9c66d363c68d4890_303964_e9673e15410217a2a4c7bb862bf2154f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Perception of likely drought.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;financial-capacity-to-pay-for-insurance&#34;&gt;Financial Capacity to Pay for Insurance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next question we asked ourselves, was if the drought risk correlates
with the ability to pay as distributed among local communities. Whether
an insurance policy – or the regulation of insurance – attempts to
provide cover on an individual level (through increased premia), or
looks for local, regional or national mitigation strategies, the
income/tax base might be an appropriate benchmark to test for financial
capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-financial-capacity-to-mitigate-drought-risk&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Financial capacity to mitigate drought risk.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/belgium_income_2018_hub7a174433f849aaff3387c877c96021f_300014_18df5ea027c9f2eaf3cd731691071414.webp 400w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/belgium_income_2018_hub7a174433f849aaff3387c877c96021f_300014_55fa0c944ecfb9f3d24ee0ca21993ed0.webp 760w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/belgium_income_2018_hub7a174433f849aaff3387c877c96021f_300014_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://eviota.eu/media/img/blogposts_2021/belgium_income_2018_hub7a174433f849aaff3387c877c96021f_300014_18df5ea027c9f2eaf3cd731691071414.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Financial capacity to mitigate drought risk.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The match between the (inverted) SPEI and total net income is less than
perfect. Some of the areas most at risk coincide with the highest-income
communities, but other threatened communities are low-income by Belgian
standards. The actual risk awareness and the financial capacity to solve
the problem are again only weakly correlated.^[2]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;correlation&#34;&gt;Correlation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s have a look at the variables on &lt;code&gt;NUTS3&lt;/code&gt; level:&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-correlation-of-the-variables&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Correlation of the variables.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/var-cor-1_hu93a5ac94c874461206dbc5e3ba932828_16200_898d1dcc10909f7ec231312858e7e566.webp 400w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/var-cor-1_hu93a5ac94c874461206dbc5e3ba932828_16200_ba2a45810a48e2158032082e40312816.webp 760w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/var-cor-1_hu93a5ac94c874461206dbc5e3ba932828_16200_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://eviota.eu/media/img/blogposts_2021/var-cor-1_hu93a5ac94c874461206dbc5e3ba932828_16200_898d1dcc10909f7ec231312858e7e566.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;672&#34;
               height=&#34;480&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Correlation of the variables.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Average SPEI&lt;/code&gt;, which is a measure of increasing humidity, is
negatively correlated with &lt;code&gt;dry&lt;/code&gt; that we defined as &lt;code&gt;-1 x avg_spei&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Dry&lt;/code&gt; areas, that are losing water, are less populous and more rich
regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Dry_18&lt;/code&gt; is a version of dry that only shows 12 months before the
Eurobarometer survey about opinions on climate change effects, to
see if the recent memory of actual weather conditions has had an
affect of the perception of Belgians about these risk. It is
seemingly not correlated with worries about floods or droughts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The&lt;code&gt;dry_18&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;dry&lt;/code&gt; variables are largely correlated. One
possible explanation is that the year before the survey was not an
unusual period, it fit very well with the 2016-2020 trend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worries about extreme weather conditions are correlated with each
other – i.e., some part of the population (concentrated
geographically) is far more concerned with climate change than
others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same on municipality (local administrative unit) level:&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-correlation-on-the-level-of-municipalities&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Correlation on the level of municipalities.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/cor-lau-1_hub6a23b7ba8396d39074c5b9dfd2a35bd_15934_6836db390a9019eedcfbf0056ccae62f.webp 400w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/cor-lau-1_hub6a23b7ba8396d39074c5b9dfd2a35bd_15934_3b84b61d8e46e482d54e71828a3e14cc.webp 760w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2021/cor-lau-1_hub6a23b7ba8396d39074c5b9dfd2a35bd_15934_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://eviota.eu/media/img/blogposts_2021/cor-lau-1_hub6a23b7ba8396d39074c5b9dfd2a35bd_15934_6836db390a9019eedcfbf0056ccae62f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;672&#34;
               height=&#34;480&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Correlation on the level of municipalities.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The correlations with opinion polling data are a little bit distorted,
because the data is on &lt;code&gt;NUTS2&lt;/code&gt;, and to bring it down to &lt;code&gt;NUTS3&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;LAU&lt;/code&gt;
level would be a complicated small area statistical estimation task. We
have also computed geospatial cross-correlation. Awareness of the
climate problem and the dryness in 2018 were positively correlated in
time – the drier the year was in an area, the more likely it was that
people are aware of the problem; and the poorer areas were more likely
to be afraid of this problem. The global spatial cross-correlation of
the drying and local income was very low. This is a neutral situation:
local income is not more concentrated to drying areas (which would be a
lucky coincidence) nor concentrated in the relatively stable areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, the problem map appears to be neutral to mildly favorable.
The financial capacity to solve the problem is not working in the favor,
nor against the problem, and awareness seems to be somewhat higher in
the more affected areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The codes are in &lt;code&gt;R/join_belgium_water_lau_dataset.R&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code&gt;R/join_belgium_water_nuts3_dataset.R&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adverse-selection-and-climate-solidarity&#34;&gt;Adverse Selection and Climate Solidarity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to these historical analyses that put the drought risk in
context, we are investigating whether climate data from integrated
climate models might be harnessed to predict medium- to longer-term risk
profiles on a spatially distributed basis. Urban planners, real estate
promoters, individual households and governments will need to rely on
such predictions to better adapt to climate change and reverse some of
the earlier policy choices we mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quote the Nobel Prize winning thoughts of Finn E. Kydland and Edward
C. Prescott (Kydland and Prescott 1977):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The issues are obvious in many well-known problems of public policy.
For example, suppose the socially desirable outcome is not to have
houses built in a particular flood plain but, given that they are there,
to take certain costly flood-control measures. If the government’s
policy were not to build the dams and levees needed for flood protection
and agents knew this was the case, even if houses were built there,
rational agents would not live in the flood plains. But the rational
agent knows that, if he and others build houses there, the government
will take the necessary flood-control measures. Consequently, in the
absence of a law prohibiting the construction of houses in the flood
plain, houses are built there, and the army corps of engineers
subsequently builds the dams and levees.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our initial explorations at least suggest that leaving the resolution
entirely to market forces, for example through increased property
insurance premia may well lead to underinsurance in poorer areas that is
&lt;em&gt;dynamically inconsistent&lt;/em&gt; with government policy. If in particular
severe drought will bankrupt farmers in such areas, eventually regional
or national government will be forced to bail them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other extreme approach, i.e., leaving the climate-change related
damages entirely to the taxpayer, therefore does not seem feasible
either with climate awareness and local income tax base only weakly
correlating with the drought patterns. In addition, drought of course
does not confine itself to municipal borders; the hydrological topology
of the issue inherently implies a coordination problem between local,
regional and federal entities passing the buck from one to another. One
can imagine some form of solidarity and redistribution will be required
to align interests and avoid adverse selection. To address these typical
market failures, government will need to step in to allow these risks,
that may be privately uninsurable, to be covered on a society-wide
basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These problems are not unique to property damage. Similar problems arise
in many student loan systems in the world (where it is desirable that
the loan can be taken by arts students or future teachers, who may not
have as high earning potential as easy-to-credit future lawyers,
engineers, managers) or in many social security issues: a minimum level
of health insurance for the unemployed and poor is desirable not only on
the basis of humanity, but to avoid epidemic risks. Such special loan
systems and special insurance systems are balancing some social welfare
with individual welfare and individual risk considerations, and at the
same time they try to avoid adverse selection, free-riding. We believe
that our example can spark some ideas how a desirable social outcome can
be aligned with the principles of insurance and personal responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, on a longer term basis, incentives that may transfer
water-intensive industrial and agricultural activities from the areas
most at risk, could be called for, as well as better hydrological
management to safeguard water reserves. We invite the authorities and
relevant stakeholders to render the appropriate data needed to assess
climate and drought evolution and to calculate risk premia scenarios and
solidarity mechanisms open data, verified for quality through unit-tests
and peer review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antal, Daniel. 2021a. &lt;em&gt;Regions: Processing Regional Statistics&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://regions.danielantal.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://regions.danielantal.eu/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. 2021b. &lt;em&gt;Retroharmonize: Ex Post Survey Data Harmonization&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://retroharmonize.dataobservatory.eu/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beguerı́a, Santiago, Sergio M Vicente-Serrano, Fergus Reig, and Borja
Latorre. 2014. “Standardized Precipitation Evapotranspiration Index
(SPEI) Revisited: Parameter Fitting, Evapotranspiration Models, Tools,
Datasets and Drought Monitoring.” &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Climatology&lt;/em&gt;
34 (10): 3001–23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European Commission. 2019. “Eurobarometer 90.2 (2018).” GESIS Data
Archive, Cologne. ZA7488 Data file Version 1.0.0,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4232/1.13289&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4232/1.13289&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.4232/1.13289&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4232/1.13289&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kydland, Finn E., and Edward C. Prescott. 1977. “Rules Rather Than
Discretion: The Inconsistency of Optimal Plans.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Political
Economy&lt;/em&gt; 85 (3): 473–91. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/1830193&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://www.jstor.org/stable/1830193&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statbel. 2020. “&lt;span class=&#34;nocase&#34;&gt;Fiscal statistics on
income&lt;/span&gt;.” Eurostat.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://statbel.fgov.be/en/open-data/fiscal-statistics-income&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://statbel.fgov.be/en/open-data/fiscal-statistics-income&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vicente-Serrano, Sergio M, Santiago Beguerı́a, and Juan I López-Moreno.
2010. “A Multiscalar Drought Index Sensitive to Global Warming: The
Standardized Precipitation Evapotranspiration Index.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of
Climate&lt;/em&gt; 23 (7): 1696–1718.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a standardized variate, SPEI can be compared across space and
time. The original calculation of SPEI is based on the FAO-56
Penman-Monteith method. Other relevant indicators might consider the
soil composition for example: clay and lime soils tend to be more
vulnerable to drought. We combined this ecological dimension with the
socio-economic dimension to suggest that insurance premia design might
be targeted to, say, income levels as well - or alternatively to real
estate prices. See (Beguerı́a et al. 2014; Vicente-Serrano, Beguerı́a, and
López-Moreno 2010)&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
