<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flowers | Eviota</title>
    <link>https://eviota.eu/tag/flowers/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://eviota.eu/tag/flowers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Flowers</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://eviota.eu/media/icon_hucb5b60c3ce6d78a39dc1b8454aefe125_21353_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Flowers</title>
      <link>https://eviota.eu/tag/flowers/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>BeeSage: Data-driven Beekeeping for Productivity and Sustainability</title>
      <link>https://eviota.eu/post/2022-10-31_beesage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eviota.eu/post/2022-10-31_beesage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BeeSage&lt;/strong&gt; is an early stage startup which is contesting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.impactcity.nl/en/service/the-hague-innovators-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Hague Innovators Award&lt;/a&gt; in the pre-startup category. They are evangelizing data-driven beekeeping for productivity and sustainability, &lt;a href=&#34;https://eviota.eu/authors/reprex&#34;&gt;Reprex&lt;/a&gt; is an impact scale-up in the other category of this competition for more mature startups that is building collaborative, open scholarly data infrastructure, so-called data observatories to support the needs of various data-driven policy, business, or scientific innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met in the &lt;code&gt;ImpactCity&lt;/code&gt; initiative of The Hague, and we&amp;rsquo;d like to build on The Hague impact startup ecosystem by combining our respective strengths so we decided to join forces! We both want to win in The Hague Innovators’ Challenge in 2022, but we only compete for the votes of the audience. Through our cooperation, we would like to increase the viability of BeeSage in the pre-startup category and increase the value proposition of Reprex in the startup category to the jury in ImpactFest.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-remote-team-of-engineers-in-the-netherlands-latvia-and-portugal&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Remote team of engineers in the Netherlands, Latvia and Portugal.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/blogposts_2022/beesage_team_huedf14d05dcfb520f96938797295da472_403435_8f2ba27f10054a4e4a3174144083d5e5.webp 400w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2022/beesage_team_huedf14d05dcfb520f96938797295da472_403435_109d4c6d8ed41d11124419fc9460ddcb.webp 760w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2022/beesage_team_huedf14d05dcfb520f96938797295da472_403435_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://eviota.eu/media/img/blogposts_2022/beesage_team_huedf14d05dcfb520f96938797295da472_403435_8f2ba27f10054a4e4a3174144083d5e5.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Remote team of engineers in the Netherlands, Latvia and Portugal.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BeeSage modular beehive monitoring system boosts productivity and honey yield to benefit the Earth through data-driven pollination. Their software and hardware such as Smart Beehive Scales help beekeepers mitigate risks and enable informed decisions, while turning every apiary into a weather station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are also building &lt;code&gt;HiveMap&lt;/code&gt; as a data analytics software, which enables beekeeper associations, environmental organizations and other stakeholders to turn beehive and remove sensing data into valuable insights. This product can be greatly enhanced through the latest data from Europe’s Copernicus satellites, from meteorological and air pollution sources. This is where Reprex’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://greendeal.dataobservatory.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Green Deal Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; comes into the picture.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-beesage-is-building-hivemap-as-a-data-analytics-software&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;BeeSage is building HiveMap as a data analytics software.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/blogposts_2022/BeeSage_hivemap_hu42f2acc367849ed681f57722b67374e5_2528808_b300b2b2a02bbada627b29cee94a0042.webp 400w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2022/BeeSage_hivemap_hu42f2acc367849ed681f57722b67374e5_2528808_f71d20f22daca28bd41fca303e42b8f1.webp 760w,
               /media/img/blogposts_2022/BeeSage_hivemap_hu42f2acc367849ed681f57722b67374e5_2528808_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://eviota.eu/media/img/blogposts_2022/BeeSage_hivemap_hu42f2acc367849ed681f57722b67374e5_2528808_b300b2b2a02bbada627b29cee94a0042.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;458&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      BeeSage is building HiveMap as a data analytics software.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beekeepers associations, small research groups, or Ecotech startups cannot afford to build a full team of data engineers, data scientists, and statisticians to tap into components of raw inflation data (to find honey price or food value chain data), to create validated and continuously maintained data pipelines from environmental satellites, the data warehouses of Eurostat and the European Environmental Agency. They cannot hire small-area statisticians and ecological regression experts to create ecological and key business indicators for small tracts of land that are directly relevant to the health of a honeybee colony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex produces open-source scientific software, and various collaborative data engineering infrastructures to get legally open governmental data and open science data in a timely, usable format to ecological researchers, beekeeper associations, and Ecotech startups like BeeSage. The European Union legally opened up vast arrays of scientific and governmental data sources for commercial and scientific reuse, but investment into re-processing and validating data that was originally collected for a different primary cause requires plenty of private investment.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-reprex-produces-open-source-scientific-softwarehttpsreprexnlreleases-and-various-collaborative-data-engineering-infrastructures-to-get-legally-open-governmental-data-and-open-science-data-in-a-timely-usable-format-to-ecological-researchers-and-ecotech-innovators&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Reprex produces [open-source scientific software](/https://reprex.nl/#releases), and various collaborative data engineering infrastructures to get legally open governmental data and open science data in a timely, usable format to ecological researchers, and ecotech innovators.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /media/img/package_screenshots/regions_package_20221101_16x9_hu243b93523dd1d220293cadf15db845f9_151150_843634b2cd40dbbd4f49d648f820996d.webp 400w,
               /media/img/package_screenshots/regions_package_20221101_16x9_hu243b93523dd1d220293cadf15db845f9_151150_199372ba733c18e0f3a1d7c7ba06cdf5.webp 760w,
               /media/img/package_screenshots/regions_package_20221101_16x9_hu243b93523dd1d220293cadf15db845f9_151150_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://eviota.eu/media/img/package_screenshots/regions_package_20221101_16x9_hu243b93523dd1d220293cadf15db845f9_151150_843634b2cd40dbbd4f49d648f820996d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;376&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure&amp;nbsp;&#34; data-post=&#34;:&amp;nbsp;&#34; class=&#34;numbered&#34;&gt;
      Reprex produces &lt;a href=&#34;https://eviota.eu/https://reprex.nl/#releases&#34;&gt;open-source scientific software&lt;/a&gt;, and various collaborative data engineering infrastructures to get legally open governmental data and open science data in a timely, usable format to ecological researchers, and ecotech innovators.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reprex’s data observatories, particularly the &lt;a href=&#34;https://eviota.eu/#slider&#34;&gt;Green Deal Data Observatory&lt;/a&gt; are public-private partnerships that foster the collective collection, processing, peer-review, and reuse of novel big data, like BeeSage’s beehive data, and reusable statistical and environmental data. We hope to place the permanent institution of this PPP in the Hague, which is already the &lt;a href=&#34;https://thehague.com/businessagency/the-hague-the-winner-world-smart-city-award-2021&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;World&amp;rsquo;s Smartest City&lt;/a&gt;, and which wants to remain a global centre of excellence of peace, justice, and sustainability in the era of big data and AI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
